我们不该树立指示牌的
We should never have put up the signs.
我们以为会发生什么事啊
What the hell did we think was gonna happen?
是我们把他们引来的
We brought them here.
我们在努力做好事
We were trying to do something good.
我们展现了人性
We were being human beings.
我们现在是什么  葛瑞
What are we now, Gareth?
如今
他们不像坏人  但我当时准备走了
They seemed nice enough, but I was ready to go.
虽然我们刚到这里  但是该死
We just got here, but, damn,
我们必须走了
it was time to go.
我跟他们说起华盛顿时
When I told them about DC,
他们的老大使了个眼色
a wink and a nod from the head asshole in charge,
他们拔出了枪  然后我们
they pulled their guns and it was right back
跟往常一样倒了霉
to our regularly scheduled shitstorm.
他们把你关进来之前  你没看见泰尔西吗
Before they put you in here, you didn't see Tyreese?
-没有  -那就好
- No. - Good.
一辆画着白十字的黑车
Black car with a white cross painted on it.
我努力跟着它  我尽力了
I tried to follow it. I tried.
她还活着吗
But she's alive?
是的
She's alive.
闭嘴
Shut up!
有四个混蛋往我们这边走来
All right, got four of them pricks coming our way.
你们都知道该怎么做
Y'all know what to do.
先攻眼
Go for their eyes first.
再插喉
Then their throats.
背靠在车厢两侧
Put your backs to the walls on either side of the car now.
快跑
Move!
等等
Okay, hold up.
好了
All right.
各位  你们射出了多少发子弹
Hey, guys. What were your shot counts?
38发
38.
你的呢
Your shot count?
该死  抱歉
Crap, man, I'm sorry.
这是我第一次围捕
It was my first roundup.
这里的事做完后  回到岗哨点
After you're done here, go back to your point
数一数弹壳
and count the shells.
凯利明天才会捡起弹壳
Kaylee won't be gathering them until tomorrow.
我要跟你说话
Hey, let me talk to you.
-A区四个  D区四个吗  -对
- Four from A, four from D? - Yeah.
让我跟你谈一会儿
Hey, let me talk to you for a minute.
Let me talk to you for a minute.
-让我跟你谈一会儿  -什么
- Let me talk to you for a minute. - What?
别这样  我们能解决这事
Don't do this. We can fix this.
-你没法解决  -你不必这样做
- No, you can't. - You don't have to do this.
我们说过了  有办法解决灾变
We told you there's a way out of all this.
你只用冒冒险
You just have to take a chance.
我们有个伙伴知道如何阻止这一切
We have a man who knows how to stop it.
他有解决方法  我们得送他去华盛顿
He has a cure. We just have to get him to Washington.
你没必要这样做
You don't have to do this, man.
我们可以让世界恢复原样
We can put the world back to how it was.
恢复不了了  鲍勃
Can't go back, Bob.
可以的  你不必这么做
We can! You don't have to do this!
我们看见你拿着包进了树林
We saw you go into the woods with a bag
出来的时候包没了
and come out without it.
我不得不调回了侦察员  所以还没去找
Had to pull my spotters back before we could go look for it.
里面有什么
What was in it?
你把它藏起来了  对吗
You hid it, right?
以防不测
In case things went bad?
聪明
Smart.
不过我们会找到的
Still, we'll find it.
但是现在出去太危险了
But it's too dangerous to go out there right now.
里面有什么
What was in it?
我很好奇
I'm curious.
那是个大包
And it was a big bag.
你真想让我这么做吗
You really gonna let me do this?
让我带你去
Well, let me take you out there.
你自己看
I'll show you.
那不可能  但这个有可能
Not gonna happen. This might.
里面有枪
There's guns in it.
AK47
AK-47.
点44马格南手枪
.44 Magnum.
自动武器  夜视镜
Automatic weapons. Nightscope.
有一把复合弓
There's a compound bow
还有一把红柄砍刀
and a machete with a red handle.
我会用那把刀杀掉你
That's what I'm gonna use to kill you.
谢谢
Thanks.
两小时内把他们弄到烘干机上
You have two hours to get them on the driers.
我要去扮红脸了
I'm gonna go back to public face.
现在可以大开杀戒
Now's the time we can get messy,
但必须在日落之前完工
but we need to dial it all in by sundown.
-明白  -遵命
- Got it. - Yes, sir.
查克
Hey, Chuck?
我们快到了
We're close.
我会把你们俩都送到那里
I'm gonna get you both there.
确保你们的安全
Make sure you're safe.
但我不会留下
But I'm not gonna stay.
我不能  现在还不能
I can't. Not yet.
你必须快点适应
You're going to have to be able to.
还有更多
More.
那个枪声
That gunfire,
可能是从终点站传来的
it could have been from Terminus.
有人在攻击他们
Someone was attacking them.
或者他们在攻击别人
Or they were attacking someone.
我们要去弄清楚吗
Do we even want to find out?
是的
Yeah.
还有一条往东的铁道  会带我们去那里
There's another track due east. It'll get us there.
我们必须小心
We'll be real careful.
我们要弄清楚
We're gonna get answers.
十分钟倒数
10-minute count.
你搞砸了就得靠自己了  马丁
You screw up, you're on your own, Martin.
不用你说  我的屁股我自己擦
You don't have to tell me. I wipe my own ass.
亚历克斯还不明白
Alex didn't get it.
看吧  我就知道刀女不是什么好鸟
See, I knew the chick with the sword was bad news.
那婊子不拿武器都像个武器
Bitch looked like a weapon with a weapon.
他总是让人不省心
He was always a sloppy-ass mother.
对  我让艾伯特给那小孩放完血后
Yeah, I told Albert I want the kid's hat
把他的帽子给我
after they bleed him out.
别碰开关  丢在地上
Keep your finger off the button and drop it.
在扮红脸前他们只宰八个人
They're only doing eight before public face.
听着  别这样
Listen, y'all don't have to do this.
你们想要什么都成  这地方欢迎每位客人
Whatever you want, we got a place where everyone's welcome.
-闭嘴  -好吧
- Shut up, man. - Okay.
你所说的那位刀女和那个戴帽子的小孩
We're friends of the chick with the sword
正是我们的朋友
and the kid in the hat.
他们攻击我们  我们只是把他们囚禁了
They attacked us. We're just holding them.
我可不相信你
I don't believe you.
你们还囚禁了谁  你知道名字吗
Who else do you have? Do you know their names?
我们只抓了男孩和武士  就他俩
We just have the boy and the samurai, that's it.
我们不过是正当防卫
We were just protecting ourselves.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
我们还有很多人
There's a bunch of us out there
六个方向都有
in six different directions.
基地那边枪战不断
There was a lot of gunfire back home.
我们必须同时点燃烟花
We need to set off our charges all at the same time
来引开行尸  这对你们也有好处
to confuse the dead ones away. That's good for you, too.
并不是
No, it isn't.
一群行尸正向终点站移动
There's a herd heading toward Terminus right now.
我们不想引开他们
We don't want to confuse them away.
我们需要他们的帮助
We're gonna need their help.
那里是个堡垒
It's a compound.
他们会发现你们的
They'll see you coming.
前提是你们能突破
If you even make it that far
走向那里的行尸群
with all the cold bodies heading over.
卡罗尔
Carol.
你打算怎么做
How are you gonna do this?
我得杀人
I'm gonna kill people.
她叫什么
She got a name?
嘿  她叫什么
Hey, she got a name?
朱迪思
Judith.
她是你女儿吗
She your daughter or something?
她是我朋友
She's a friend.
我没有朋友
I don't have any friends.
虽然我认识一些人
I mean, I know people.
但他们不过是一起搭伙的混蛋罢了
They're just assholes I stay alive with.
那个女人也是你朋友吗
The other one your friend? The woman?
我以前也有朋友
I used to have them.
周末约在一起看橄榄球
Used to watch football on Sundays.
一起去教堂
Went to church.
我知道我有过
I know I did.
但我现在想不起来他们了
But I can't picture it anymore.
真可笑  浑浑噩噩过了这么久
It's funny how you don't even notice the time go by.
每天糟糕的事不断
Horrible shit just stacks up day after day.
最后就习惯了
You get used to it.
我还没有习惯
I haven't gotten used to it.
你当然没有了
Of course you haven't.
你是那种会救小宝宝的人
You're the kind of guy who saves babies.
就像是当你被困在大海中间
It's kind of like saving an anchor
没有船  却要死抱着船锚不放一样
when you're stuck without a boat in the middle of the ocean.
遇到什么心结了  是不是
Been behind some kind of walls, right?
你还活着
You're still around,
但是你却没干过脏活  我看得出来
but you haven't had to get your hands dirty. I can tell.
瞧  你是个好人
See, you're a good guy.
你完全不知道我干过什么
You have no idea about the things I've done.
你是个好人
You're a good guy.
这就是为什么你今天会死
That's why you're gonna die today.
这就是为什么这个宝宝也会死
It's why the baby is going to die.
或者...
Or...
你可以坐上那辆车
you can get in that car,
离开这里
get out of here,
继续幸存下去
keep on being lucky.
你以为你会杀了我吗
You think you're gonna kill me?
你怎么还没杀了我
Why haven't you killed me?
让我活着对你有什么好处
How...How does having me alive help you?
你为什么还要和我说话
Why the hell are you even talking to me?
带上她
Take her,
开上车子
take the car,
离开这里
and go.
我今天不想做这种事
I don't want to do this today.
是终点站吗
Is that Terminus?
是的
Yeah.
也许吧
Probably.
说不定这次你会赢
Maybe you're gonna win this.
说不定你的朋友
Maybe your friend--
我是说
I mean,
说不定那个女人
maybe that woman
被枪杀了
just got capped.
说不定等她回来了
Maybe I'm gonna be the one who gets capped
我会被枪杀
when she comes back.
今天没有人会死
Nobody's got to die today.
伙计  假如你真这么想
Man, if you believe that...
那死的人一定是你和那个小孩
then it's definitely gonna be you and the kid.
就算那个地方已经化为灰烬了
Even if that place is burning to the ground.
刚刚他妈是怎么回事
Hey, what the hell was that?
听到了吗
Do you copy?
你们留在这里
You stay here.
葛瑞  这些人又逃不走
Gareth, these guys aren't going anywhere.
在我搞清情况之前  留在这里
Stay here until I know what's happening.
那我们就干坐着吗
So we just sit here?
我们还有工作
Got a job to do.
天呐
Oh, Jesus.
在吗  葛瑞
You there, Gareth?
他忙着呢
He's busy.
你闻到烟味了吗
You smell the smoke?
听到枪响了吗  他说不定已经死了
You hear the shots? He could be dead.
我们待在这里干嘛  这里可能会被炸飞
The hell we doing here? The whole place could be going up.
你刚执了一回勤就违反规矩
You went on one roundup and you blew protocol.
我们不用担心安保  那不是我们的工作
We don't deal with security. That ain't our job.
这才是  看着我
This is. Hey, look at me.
干嘛
What?
不要啊
No, no, no, no, no!
瑞克
Rick!
到底是怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
-有人袭击他们了  -可能我们的人逃了
- Someone hit them. - Maybe our people got free.
借过
Excuse me.
你这是在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
我或许可以用这个弹壳把门打开
I might be able to use this shell to compromise the door.
听外面的情况
From the sound of things,
可能没人会给咱们开门了
there may not be anybody left to open it.
尤金  抱歉  闭嘴
Eugene, I'm sorry, but shut up.
好的
Okay.
我爸会回来的
My dad's gonna be back.
-他们都会回来的  -会的
- They all are. - They are.
他们回来的时候
And we need to get ready
我们要准备好  杀出一条血路
to fight our way out with them when they do.
如果他们遇到麻烦  我们就有机会了
If they got problems, we got a chance.
像是炸弹爆炸的声音
It sounded like a bomb.
像是打仗的声音
Sounds like a damn war.
就在那
Right there.
他们到底是什么人
What the hell are these people?
他们不是人
They ain't people.
别杀他
Don't.
让他尸变吧
Let him turn.
遇到他们的人  格杀勿论
Cross any of these people, you kill them.
别手软
Don't hesitate.
他们不会手软的
They won't.
我们跑的话  就可以摆脱它们
If we run, we can get by them.
它们无暇顾及
They're distracted.
我们得把那些人救出来
We got to let those people out.
我们的人性还在
That's still who we are.
必须得救他们
It's got to be.
救救我
Help me!
快快快
Come on, come on, come on.
我们是一样的
We're the same!
我们跟他们一样
We're them!
走开
Back off!
我们是一样的
We're the same.
快走
Come on.
-我们必须原路返回  -A区在那边
- We got to double back. - A is that way.
我们回去的话就找不到路了
We go back, we don't know where we are.
我们别无选择  对吗
We don't really have a choice, do we?
-在这等着  -瑞克  瑞克
- Wait here. - Rick. Rick!
装弹
Reloading!
我们必须原路返回
We're going to have to double back.
放下武器  转过身来
Drop your weapons and turn around.
我想看看你的脸
I want to see your face.
快
Now!
那些标语
The signs...
是真的
They were real.
这里曾是个避难所
It was a sanctuary.
可有人来夺取了这地方
People came and took this place.
-我只想知道...-他们强奸  杀人
- Just tell me where-- - And they raped and they killed
还大笑
and they laughed
持续了好几周
over weeks.
但我们逃出去了
But we got out
然后我们战斗  夺回了这里
and we fought and we got it back.
从那时起  我们懂了
And we heard the message.
不当屠夫
You're the butcher...
便为羔羊
or you're the cattle.
从车厢里带出来的人  他们在哪
The men they pulled from that train car, where are they?
他们在哪
Where are they?
现在
Now...
对准我的头吧
point it at my head.
你本可以成为我们的一员
You could have been one of us.
你本可以听到上天的旨意
You could have listened to what the world is telling you.
你们引诱人们来这里
You lead people here and
洗劫他们  再杀掉他们
you take what they have and you kill them?
这地方是做这种事的吗
Is that what this place is?
不  最初并不是
No, not at first.
可我们不得不这样
It's what it had to be.
所以我们还在这里活着
And we're still here.
你不算活着
You're not here.
我也要走了
Neither am I.
不  不  不
No! No! No!
不  天啊
Oh! No, God!
不  不
No! No!
后退
Back off!
把武器放在地上
Put your weapons on the ground.
现在踢过来
Kick them over right now.
快
Right now!
求你
Please.
求你  不要
Please, don't.
别伤害她
Don't hurt her.
出去
Go outside.
Go outside!
我一扭她就死  伙计
Just one twist, man.
-不要  -别逼我
- Don't! - Don't make me!
出去
Go outside.
好
All right.
辛西娅  听到吗
Cynthia, do you copy?
对  就该这样
Yeah. That's how it works.
我做不到
I won't.
I won't!
我做不到
解决方法是什么  尤金
What's the cure, Eugene?
这是机密
It's classified.
我们不知道会发生什么
We don't know what's gonna happen.
你别烦他了
You leave him be.
我们应该继续忙活
We need to keep working.
是啊  但现在该听听了
Yeah, but it's time to hear it.
因为我们不知道接下来会发生什么
'Cause we don't know what's coming next.
我们下一步就是从这里逃出去
What's next is we get out of this.
就算我全盘托出
Even if I told you all,
就算我提供一步一步的指示
even if I provided step-by-step instructions
配上插图和精心编排的常见问题
complete with illustrations and a well-composed FAQ
如果我出了意外
and I went red-ring,
解决方法也会随我而亡
the cure would still die with me.
我不会让你出事的
I'm not gonna let that happen.
最好的情况就是
The best-case scenario,
我们走出去面对子弹  大火和行尸
we step out into a hellstorm of bullets, fire, and walkers.
我不是飞毛腿
I'm not fleet of foot.
肯定不可能靠
I sure as hell can't take a dead one down
钝器和信心放倒行尸
with sharp buttons and hella confidence.
是啊  但是我们可以  而且我们会的
Yeah, but we can and we will.
你不欠我们的
You don't owe us anything.
到目前为止
Not yet.
但我们就是想听听你的计划
But we just want to hear it.
你们没必要这样做
You don't have to.
我是人类基因组计划
I was part of a 10-person team
十人小组的一员  我们将疾病改造为武器
at the Human Genome Project to weaponize diseases
对抗已武器化的疾病
to fight weaponized diseases.
用致病微生物对抗致病微生物
Pathogenic microorganisms with pathogenic microorganisms.
以毒攻毒
Fire with fire.
不同部门间喝过酒
Interdepartmental drinks were had,
建立起了关系  共享信息
relationships made, information shared.
我对自动防止故障的传送系统
I am keenly aware of all the details
背后的运作细节了如指掌
behind fail-safe delivery systems
其目的是杀光这个星球上所有的活人
to kill every living person on this planet.
我认为  对华盛顿的终端略作调整
I believe with a little tweaking on the terminals in DC,
我们就可以扭转局势
we can flip the script.
干掉所有行尸
Take out every last dead one of them.
以毒攻毒
Fire with fire.
一切顺利的话  听起来还是很炫酷的嘛
All things being equal, it does sound pretty badass.
所以  我们继续忙活吧
So let's get back to work.
快点  一路杀到栅栏边
Come on! Fight to the fence!
不要离开他
Do not leave his side!
-快快快  -卡尔
- Go, go, go! - Carl!
快跟上  我们走吧
Come on. Let's go!
爬过去
Up and over.
我们走  快点
Let's go! Move!
快点
Come on!
在这里
Right here.
我们还待在这里做什么
The hell are we still around here for?
枪支  还有补给
Guns, and some supplies.
围着栅栏走  用步枪
Go along the fences. Use the rifles.
干掉剩下的人
Take out the rest of 'em.
什么
What?
他们没资格活下去
They don't get to live.
瑞克  我们逃出来了  结束了
Rick, we got out. It's over.
他们死光才算结束
It's not over till they're all dead.
当然结束了  那里着火了
The hell it isn't. That place is on fire.
里面全是行尸
Full of walkers.
我可不会为这种蠢事浪费时间
I'm not dicking around with this crap.
我们刚刚才逃出来
We just made it out.
栅栏倒了
The fences are down.
他们要么逃  要么死
They'll run or die.
那是你做的吗
Did you do that?
你们必须跟我来
You have to come with me.
朱迪斯  你没事
Judith. You're okay.
发生了什么
What happened?
来了一群行尸
There were a bunch of walkers out here
他掐着朱迪斯
and he got his hands around Judith's neck.
别  他死了
No, he's dead.
我必须做
I-- I had to.
所以我做了
So I did.
我能做到
I could.
我不知道火是不是还在烧
I don't know if the fire is still burning.
S04E14中米卡曾说"黑烟代表仍在燃烧"
还在烧呢
It is.
是啊  我们得走了
Yeah. We need to go.
好  但是去哪里
Yeah, but where?
离那里越远越好
Somewhere far away from there.
我们会跟他说的
We'll talk to him.
但不是现在
Not just yet.
无处避难
过去
妈妈
Mom! Mom.
不
No!
那个
That one.
不  求你们了  不要再来了
No, no, please. Not again.
不
No! No!
没事的
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay. -- It's okay.
不  有事
No, it's not.
我们会夺回这里
We're gonna take it back.
怎么夺回
How?
我们会的
We will.
不当屠夫  便为羔羊
You're either the butcher or the cattle.